<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Simply Track Time</title>
    <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Simply Track Time</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 21:21:13 +1200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Focus: Strategies to Minimize Interruptions and Boost Work Productivity</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2024-09-19-mastering-focus-strategies-to-minimize-interruptions-and-boost-work-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 21:21:13 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2024-09-19-mastering-focus-strategies-to-minimize-interruptions-and-boost-work-productivity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today’s fast-paced and interconnected world, interruptions are an inevitable part of our daily work life. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s a ping from a messaging app, a phone call, or a colleague stopping by for a quick chat, interruptions can significantly impact our work productivity. In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore the effects of interruptions on work productivity and discuss strategies for minimizing their negative impact.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the most noticeable effects of interruptions on work productivity is the disruption of focus. When we are interrupted, especially during tasks requiring deep concentration, it can take a significant amount of time to regain focus and get back into the flow of work. Studies have shown that it can take up to 23 minutes to fully recover our focus after an interruption, leading to a significant loss of productive time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Goals over a Break</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2024-03-14-goals-over-a-break/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 21:21:13 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2024-03-14-goals-over-a-break/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to the American Time Use Survey, adults in the United States spend an average of 3.6 hours per day on leisure and sports activities, 2.8 hours per day on household activities, and 2.6 hours per day on work and work-related activities. Despite this, a study by the American Psychological Association found that 44% of Americans say their stress levels have increased over the past five years, and 20% say they experience extreme stress. On the other hand, a study by the National Institute of Mental Health found that self-care can reduce stress, improve mood, and increase overall well-being.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resolutions</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2024-02-14-resolutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 21:21:13 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2024-02-14-resolutions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to the American Time Use Survey, adults in the United States spend an average of 3.6 hours per day on leisure and sports activities, 2.8 hours per day on household activities, and 2.6 hours per day on work and work-related activities. Despite this, a study by the American Psychological Association found that 44% of Americans say their stress levels have increased over the past five years, and 20% say they experience extreme stress. On the other hand, a study by the National Institute of Mental Health found that self-care can reduce stress, improve mood, and increase overall well-being.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Balance Your Time Between All Elements of Your Life</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2024-01-14-how-to-balance-your-time-between-all-elements-of-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 21:21:13 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2024-01-14-how-to-balance-your-time-between-all-elements-of-your-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to the American Time Use Survey, adults in the United States spend an average of 3.6 hours per day on leisure and sports activities, 2.8 hours per day on household activities, and 2.6 hours per day on work and work-related activities. Despite this, a study by the American Psychological Association found that 44% of Americans say their stress levels have increased over the past five years, and 20% say they experience extreme stress. On the other hand, a study by the National Institute of Mental Health found that self-care can reduce stress, improve mood, and increase overall well-being.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Holidays!</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-11-14-holidays/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 21:21:13 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-11-14-holidays/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The holiday season is upon us, and while it&amp;rsquo;s a time of relaxation, it can also be an excellent opportunity to be productive. With some planning and effort, you can make the most of your holiday and return refreshed and ready to tackle the new year. Here are some tips on how to have a productive holiday.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Set realistic goals: Before you start your holiday, make a list of things you want to accomplish. Be realistic about your goals, and prioritise the most critical tasks. This will help you stay focused and avoid feeling overwhelmed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Studying Pressure</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-11-07-studying-pressure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 21:21:13 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-11-07-studying-pressure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As exam season approaches, stress levels tend to skyrocket. It can be hard to manage the pressure of studying, preparing and performing well, all while dealing with the added pressures of daily life. However, there are ways to cope with this stress that can help you stay calm and focused during this challenging time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Firstly, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to stay organised. Make a study schedule that breaks down your work into manageable chunks. This will help you to avoid last-minute cramming and reduce the feeling of being overwhelmed. Keeping a planner or using an app like Google Calendar can help you stay on top of your work and ensure you don&amp;rsquo;t miss any critical deadlines.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swamped</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-11-07-swamped/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 21:21:13 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-11-07-swamped/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Feeling like work is sucking the life out of you? Or are you just feeling swamped with your tasks? Taking a break could be the answer to your problems. Giving yourself some time to recharge can work wonders for both your body and mind. Here are some benefits of kicking back and taking a break from the grind.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Firstly, taking a break can help ease stress levels. Stress can affect your body and mind, causing fatigue, headaches, and anxiety. By taking a break, you allow yourself to chill out and recharge, which can help reduce your stress levels.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stress</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-10-09-stress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 21:21:13 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-10-09-stress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dealing with stress can be a challenging task, especially when you&amp;rsquo;re juggling multiple responsibilities. It&amp;rsquo;s essential to take care of your mental health to avoid burnout and maintain a healthy work-life balance. Here are some tips that can help you manage stress effectively:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Exercise regularly: Physical activity can significantly reduce stress levels and improve your mood. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s a quick walk or a full workout, make time for exercise in your daily routine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ways to stay focussed</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-10-09-ways-to-stay-focussed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 21:21:13 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-10-09-ways-to-stay-focussed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As we go about our daily lives, we tend to underestimate just how much time we spend on various activities. From scrolling through social media to completing work assignments, time seems to slip away from us without us even realizing it. This is where tracking your time can come in handy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tracking your time involves keeping a record of how you spend your time throughout the day. It may seem tedious at first, but the benefits are well worth it. Here are some of the positives of tracking your time:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exam Time</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-09-25-exam-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 21:21:13 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-09-25-exam-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We all know the stress that comes with exams. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to feel overwhelmed and need help figuring out where to start. That&amp;rsquo;s why having a plan in place is crucial to manage your study time effectively. Here are some tips to help you prepare for your exams and stay organised.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, create a study schedule. This will help you break down your study time into manageable chunks and ensure you cover all the necessary material. Allocate time for each subject and take regular breaks to avoid burnout.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stick to the plan</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-09-25-stick-to-the-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 21:21:13 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-09-25-stick-to-the-plan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As we all go through life, it can be challenging to manage our time effectively. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a student, a professional, or a stay-at-home parent, there are always demands on your time. Creating a schedule is one of the best ways to stay organised and reduce stress.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to set realistic goals for yourself. Determine your priorities and what tasks are most important to you. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s work, family, or personal projects, allocate enough time for each task. It&amp;rsquo;s crucial to balance your responsibilities and your leisure time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cost of Tech.</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-09-04-cost-of-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 21:21:13 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-09-04-cost-of-tech/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Technology has undoubtedly revolutionised our daily lives, including how we experience time. From how we work to how we communicate, technology has profoundly impacted our relationship with time, both positively and negatively.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the most significant ways technology has changed our relationship with time is through the concept of &amp;ldquo;always-on&amp;rdquo; connectivity. Thanks to smartphones, laptops, and other devices, we can now access information and communicate with others at any time, from anywhere. While this has undoubtedly increased efficiency and productivity, it has also blurred the boundaries between work and personal life, making it more challenging to disconnect and unwind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perception</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-09-04-perception/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 21:21:13 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-09-04-perception/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Throughout history, humans&amp;rsquo; perception of material items has undergone significant changes. From the earliest days of civilisation to the present day, people have attached unique meanings to various things, and their significance has evolved.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In ancient times, people regarded particular objects as sacred, imbued with magical powers or spiritual significance. For example, ancient Egyptians believed that certain things, such as amulets and talismans, could protect them from harm and bring them good fortune. Similarly, many ancient cultures believed that precious metals and gemstones possessed mystical properties that could enhance their lives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memories</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-08-28-memories/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 21:21:13 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-08-28-memories/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Time plays a profound role in shaping our memories and experiences as we move through life. From the earliest moments of childhood to the final years of age, the passage of time influences how we perceive the world around us, remember the past, and plan for the future.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the most significant ways that time shapes our memories and experiences is by providing a framework for our sense of self. Our memories are not just isolated snapshots of the past; they are woven into a narrative that gives us a sense of who we are and where we come from. This narrative is shaped by the events and experiences we have had over time, and it is constantly evolving as new experiences are added to the mix.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ruts</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-08-28-ruts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 21:21:13 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-08-28-ruts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Feeling as though the world is happening around you and you are not moving anywhere can be a genuine and scary feeling. Feeling as though you are just going through the motions, with no real purpose or direction, can be frustrating and overwhelming.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Being stuck in a rut can happen for many reasons. Maybe you&amp;rsquo;ve been doing the same job for years, and it&amp;rsquo;s lost its excitement, or perhaps you&amp;rsquo;ve fallen into a routine that doesn&amp;rsquo;t challenge you. Whatever the reason, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to recognize that you don&amp;rsquo;t have to stay stuck.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Looking forward</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-08-13-looking-forward/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 21:21:13 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-08-13-looking-forward/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We all need something to look forward to in life. It gives us a sense of purpose, motivation, and hope. Having something to look forward to can be as simple as meeting a friend for coffee or as big as planning a trip to a foreign country. Regardless of the size or significance, having something to look forward to can be a positive force in our lives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest benefits of always having something to look forward to is that it can help us stay focused and motivated. When we have a goal or event on the horizon, we tend to be more productive and efficient with our time. We prioritize what needs to be done in order to reach our goal or attend our event. This can lead to a sense of accomplishment and fulfilment when we finally get to experience what we&amp;rsquo;ve been looking forward to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Procrastinate</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-08-13-procrastinate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 21:21:13 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-08-13-procrastinate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many of us tend to procrastinate until the very last minute when it comes to deadlines. However, when the deadline is far into the future, it can be easy to fall into a false sense of security and put off working on the task until it becomes urgent. In order to stay productive and avoid feeling overwhelmed later on, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to start working towards the deadline as soon as possible. Here are some tips to help you stay productive when there is a deadline very far into the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Habits to break</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-07-28-habits-to-break/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 21:21:13 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-07-28-habits-to-break/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;5 Habits to Break to Become More Productive:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These bad habits lead to low productivity. If you are doing any of these, you are inflicting yourself with more stress than necessary. So break them today and free yourself from unneeded stress and effort.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While multitasking can seem like a good idea at the time, it can lead to starting many tasks but not really finishing any. Instead, try to concentrate on tasks that are important and finish them before starting anything else.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Juggling</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-07-07-juggling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 21:21:13 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-07-07-juggling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you finding it tough to juggle your work and personal life while working a 9-5 job? It can be challenging, but managing your time effectively can make all the difference and help you achieve a healthy work-life balance. Here are some friendly tips to help you manage your time better:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Make a to-do list: Start by making a to-do list and prioritize your tasks based on their importance and urgency. This will help you stay focused and avoid procrastination.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pondering</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-07-07-pondering/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 21:21:13 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-07-07-pondering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Time is a fascinating concept. It is a strange thing - intangible yet omnipresent, fleeting yet eternal. Some people would even argue whether it exists or not. Despite this and whether you believe in time, it is indisputable that time is fleeting and making the most of what little we have can feel like a losing game.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s interesting to think about how different cultures and societies perceive time. Some view it as a precious commodity to be savoured and treasured, while others see it as a precious resource to be utilized and maximized. And yet, no matter how we view it, time remains a fundamental part of our existence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Failure</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-07-05-failure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 21:21:13 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-07-05-failure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Failing can be tough, but it&amp;rsquo;s important to remember that it&amp;rsquo;s a part of life. Everyone experiences failures at some point. It&amp;rsquo;s how we handle those failures that truly defines us. When we experience setbacks, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to lose motivation and feel like giving up. However, it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to keep pushing forward and stay motivated.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One way to stay motivated after a failure is to focus on the lessons learned. Instead of dwelling on what went wrong, try to see what you can learn from the experience. Reflect on what you could have done differently, and use that knowledge to improve your approach moving forward. By focusing on the lessons learned, you can turn a failure into a valuable learning experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gratitude</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-07-05-gratitude/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 21:21:13 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-07-05-gratitude/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As humans, we often find ourselves comparing ourselves to others. It&amp;rsquo;s natural to want to know how we measure up against those around us. However, constant comparison can be toxic and lead to feelings of inadequacy and low self-esteem.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One way to deal with comparison is to focus on your journey. Everyone has their own unique path in life, and it&amp;rsquo;s important to remember that we all have different strengths and weaknesses. Celebrate your successes and be kind to yourself when things don&amp;rsquo;t go as planned.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distracted</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-06-18-distracted/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 21:21:13 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-06-18-distracted/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Distractions are everywhere. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s your phone buzzing with notifications, your co-worker stopping by your desk to chat, or even your wandering thoughts, staying focused can be challenging. However, with the right strategies and mindset, you can learn to manage distractions and get more done in less time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Identify your biggest distractions&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first step in managing distractions is to identify what&amp;rsquo;s distracting you. Take a few minutes to reflect on your workday and list what distracts you from your tasks. Is it social media? Email notifications? Co-workers dropping by your desk? Once you know what your biggest distractions are, you can take steps to minimise their impact.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Say No</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-06-18-say-no/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 21:21:13 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-06-18-say-no/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Throughout life, we often take on more than we can handle. We may hesitate to say no to friends, colleagues, or family members who need our help. However, learning to say no can be a powerful tool for optimizing your productivity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To focus on what truly matters, you must set clear boundaries and prioritize your time. Saying no to tasks that do not align with your goals or values frees up your time and energy to focus on what is important to you. Saying no is not a rejection of you but rather a recognition of your limits.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teenager</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-06-06-teenager/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 21:39:16 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-06-06-teenager/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With so much going on in your life as a teenager, it can be hard to have a healthy schedule and good time management habits, so here are seven tips to help keep your life on track.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The first thing to do is to figure out what type of rhythm you have. Everyone has different periods during the day when they are more productive, so working out when these are for you and scheduling your life around them can help increase your productivity.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Work out ways to manage your stress. Internal stress is caused by pressures put on you, whereas external stress is caused by deadlines and factors outside. Starting projects and doing the things causing you stress is the best way to deal with external pressure, and practising mindfulness and long walks help with internal stress.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Gain an understanding of your priorities. Short-term fun is less beneficial than working towards long-term goals, but in the moment, it can be hard to see it from that point of view. Making dream boards or writing down your aims can be an easy way to consistently remind yourself what is important to you and what you need to do to get there.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start tasks early. Building healthy habits and learning not to procrastinate is an essential skill. While tasks like homework are more manageable at the beginning of high school, they will only get worse and more time-consuming. So learning to be diligent will be beneficial.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Set up a calendar and always keep track of the time. Being late and missing appointments/due dates is never fun, so looking at the time on your phone and setting up reminders on your calendar is an easy way to mitigate this.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Find ways to limit distractions and tech use. While technology can be helpful with studying and academics, it also comes with many distractions, so finding ways to limit your time looking at distractions can be very beneficial.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Do not only make to-do lists. While a to-do list is an excellent way to track what you must do, more is required. You also need to block out time to work on your tasks on the list, which can be done by creating a schedule for yourself.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tomatos?</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-06-06-tomatos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 21:38:53 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-06-06-tomatos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tomatos&#34;&gt;Tomatos?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A highly recommended way of managing time is the 45-15 rule, developed by Brett Mckay. This rule dictates that you do 45 minutes of work and then 15 minutes of play. In theory, the 15 minutes allows your brain to relax and decompress from working so that you can be more productive while working in the 45 minutes. This method focuses on preventing boredom and burnout by making your work time more efficient.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multitasking</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-06-06-multitasking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 21:21:13 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-06-06-multitasking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In&lt;/em&gt; today&amp;rsquo;s fast-paced world, it&amp;rsquo;s tempting to tackle multiple tasks simultaneously. After all, if we can accomplish numerous things simultaneously, we&amp;rsquo;ll be more productive, right? Unfortunately, that&amp;rsquo;s not necessarily the case. In fact, multitasking can actually hurt your time management skills and make you less productive overall.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s why: when you try to do multiple tasks simultaneously, your brain must switch between them constantly. This constant switching takes time and mental energy and can make you less efficient. Studies have shown that multitasking can reduce productivity by as much as 40%.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boxes of time</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-05-28-boxes-of-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 21:39:47 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-05-28-boxes-of-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Time boxing is a time management method. It involves setting a fixed amount of time for an activity in advance and then you complete the activity within the given time frame. This method uses Parkinson’s Law - “Work expands so as to fill the time available for its completion”. An example is if you have an essay due in a month, you will subconsciously aim to expand the task meaning that you will not finish the job earlier than the selected month. Using time boxing, you can cut down the time and not let the task fill the time available.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Freedom</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-05-20-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 21:39:43 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-05-20-freedom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Going from a highly structured environment like high school or even full time work to university where almost everything is self-motivated (especially with the shift to having recorded lectures) can be a difficult one for many people. So making this change successfully and finding ways to keep your motivation to study up (even when you just want to watch TikTok in bed) takes a lot of effort. But having some easy methods to fall back on that you know work every time for you is going to help a lot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Priority matrix</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-05-14-priority-matrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 21:39:40 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-05-14-priority-matrix/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Priority Matrix is a customisable tool you can use to identify critical tasks or projects. It can range in simplicity from a simple chart that contrasts urgency and importance to a much more complex grid that will look at many different criteria. The matrix is the most effective when used to rank upcoming projects. Because it is customisable you can choose criteria that are better suited to your needs, as everyone is different.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eat the frogs first</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-05-01-eat-the-frogs-first/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 21:39:36 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-05-01-eat-the-frogs-first/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mark Twain once said that if you have to eat a frog, do it first thing and nothing worse will happen for the rest of the day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The time management stratgey of eating the frog is a priotization and a productvity method, designed to help people identify diffcult tasks, so that they can complete them first. Putting the method into practice is quite simple. Think of the task you would least like to do the next day, maybe just before you go to bed, and then wake up the next morning and complete that task first thing. If there are two ‘frogs’ then eat the larger one first and so on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apps that help</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-04-30-apps-that-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 21:39:33 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-04-30-apps-that-help/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are lots of great time management apps out there. These can be a small addition to your everyday life which will help you manage your time better. The apps are great for university students in particular but can be suitable for anyone.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first app is called OWaves. This app has daily wheels you can edit by adding different tasks to fill in every moment of your day. The app works by dragging in each job and customising the task length. Certain waves you can save to use again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Planning</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-04-23-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 21:39:27 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-04-23-planning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Planning is a highly important skill to have, it can benefit your quality of life in many ways. Having a solid planning method is a way to ensure that your plans will be as good as they can be because, as we all know, plans do not always work out.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Keeping that in mind, here is a step-by-step process to ensure your plans work out as often as possible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first step is to truly understand where you stand in life. To end up where you want to be, it is important to know where you are starting from. And if you are not honest with yourself about where you stand, then you will almost certainly fail.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diary</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-04-16-diary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 21:39:24 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-04-16-diary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are many benefits to keeping a diary, especially in terms of your mental health and keeping track of time. To futher explain the benefits here are six things which are benefical about keeping a diary or journal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Diaries help to keep our thoughts organised. In them you can record events that occur daily, thoughts and feelings about these events and other things that happen in your life.&#xA;Writing in a diary can help your writing improve. To improve on something practicing often is the best method to use. So using a diary as a way to write often can be highly beneficial.&#xA;A diary cna be used to set and achieve your goals. Writing down ambitions has been proven to help you achieve them. By writing them down you can keep better track of your progress and stay motivated to reach your next milestone.&#xA;In a journal you can brain dump. This allows you to write down your frustrations, anxieties and issues. Doing so allows you to reduce stress which can accumulate overtime. Writing down everything you think of at a set point in the day, such as the morning or night time will let you have a constant point when you can release all of your stresses.&#xA;Using a diary will let you self-reflect. Having a consistent place you can look back on to see how you feel and think about certain things can be really beneficial as you can easily see how you have grown and changed as a person. It lets us stop and take a step back and reflect on ourselves.&#xA;Finally journaling can help improve your memory. Writing things down can help you remember them better. As your brain will make a stronger connection to the information you have learnt after writing it down.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A tale of two theories (of time)</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-04-10-a-tale-of-two-theories-of-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 21:39:21 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-04-10-a-tale-of-two-theories-of-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;static&lt;/strong&gt; theory of time and the &lt;strong&gt;dynamic&lt;/strong&gt; theory of time are two different theories as to how time works. According to the static theory, time is similar to space, and the passage of time does not exist. Whereas the dynamic theory believes time is very different from space and that the passage of time is actual. Clearly, these two theories are opposing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is essential to understand the differences in-depth between these two theories. So five important factors of each theory will be discussed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parkinsons law</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-04-03-parkinsons-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 21:39:18 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-04-03-parkinsons-law/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed when completing tasks that it amounts to the time you are given. If you have three hours to write three articles in an exam or three hours to write one article, it will take you all three hours to finish that task. This theory is called Parkinson’s law. Cyril Northcote Parkinson first coined it in an essay for The Economist in 1955. In his essay, he refers to a woman writing a postcard, a task that would take the average person 10 minutes; instead, this woman manages to drag the job out to become her day&amp;rsquo;s work. She spends so long choosing the postcard, writing out her message, walking to the postbox and so on that this ordinary task takes much longer than it needs to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scheduling</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-03-18-scheduling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 21:39:13 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-03-18-scheduling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Scheduling and planning are two terms often used in time management; however, these two terms can be confused easily. Planning primarily refers to what and how much must be done, whereas scheduling refers to when operations will be performed and by whom. While they are both different processes, understanding the differences and what makes each term itself helps ensure more efficiency in your time productivity in all situations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Planning is creating a plan. In a commercial sense, ensuring time and resources are appropriately allocated is crucial. In simple terms, planning looks at the what and how of a project. In comparison, scheduling is timing and establishing when to do something is the best time. To look at it in simple terms again, it is the when of a project.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting things done</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-03-12-getting-things-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 21:39:10 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-03-12-getting-things-done/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The getting things done method is a productivity system. The system was developed and explained in David Allen&amp;rsquo;s book “Getting Things Done”. It is a time and productivity management system to help people de-stress their busy lives. It uses calendars and lists to implement the new method, making your life less stressful.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The base idea is writing down your to-do list, which will help ensure you remember everything necessary. This list will reduce stress as you are not constantly trying to remember what you must do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The physics of time.</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-03-06-the-physics-of-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 21:39:07 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-03-06-the-physics-of-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is time? Looking into a definition of time, we end up with the answer that time is “the progression of events from the past to the present into the future.” (this is the definition provided by physicists.) Some consider it to be a sort of fourth dimension of our reality. While we can not sense it through touch, smell, or taste, we can measure that time has passed. And as we all know, the clock cannot be rewound, so it is an ever-present forward marching concept.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creative people</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-02-27-creative-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 21:39:02 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-02-27-creative-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Time management for people working in creative fields can take more work. This difficulty comes from many places; some reasons could be that they are doing lots but often do not want what they want to be doing or what they count as work—creatives (people working in creative fields, e.g. writers, artists etc.). Performing on big projects that do not have deadlines and are very unstructured can also contribute to their difficulty tracking time. Also, no definitive rewards often wait until the end of the large projects, so there is nothing to work towards; instead, you need pure motivation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Working</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-02-23-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 21:38:37 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-02-23-working/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During this university break, I was fortunate enough to get a job working 9-5. The change in schedule from having hour-long lectures and tutorials to an eight-hour workday, where you are working non-stop, was a hard mental shift to make. I was more productive being able to manage my time in a university schedule. Compared to performing this job, there are many moments in a day when I daze off and completely lose focus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Routine</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-02-14-routine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 21:38:59 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-02-14-routine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A routine is a conscious way of doing things in a repetitive and specific order. Most often, routines are made up of several habits combined to reach a goal. A study published by the National Centre for Biotechnology Information found that good daily habits early on in life lead to a successful life. In contrast, bad habits often lead to negative behaviour, such as dropping out of school.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Establishing a healthy morning routine is a great way to improve your life and set yourself up for success. An example of a healthy routine is waking up at 7 am going for a 30-minute walk outside, taking a shower and then eating breakfast. This way, you begin your day with purpose and consistency, meaning that your life can be managed. Routines can help you cope with many struggles, such as change, stressful situations, and mental health.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Treating uni like a 9-5</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-02-14-treating-uni-like-a-9-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 21:38:56 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-02-14-treating-uni-like-a-9-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A way of approaching university that many people promote is treating it like a 9-5 job. A full course load at university amounts to 45 hours a week, equating to a full-time job. Even though you can avoid doing most of this work (I know I could improve at finishing all of my readings), you should still spend the time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tracking the amount of time you spend studying should be the first step in trying this approach. Working out how many hours of classwork you have (in terms of tutorials, laboratories and lectures) would be the first thing to do. Then see how many readings, and schedule time to work on assessments. Keeping these hours regular is the next step. Working eight hours a day with scheduled breaks Monday to Friday is the way to approach it. For instance, if your first lecture is at 8:30 am, you are on the clock until 4:30 pm.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is time tracking?</title>
      <link>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-02-14-what-is-time-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 21:38:33 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.simplytracktime.com/post/2023-02-14-what-is-time-tracking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is time tracking? In many scenarios, it is the process of employers logging the hours employees have worked to compensate them correctly and to ensure they are using their time appropriately. An example of this is a time sheet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, looking more broadly at time management, time tracking can easily apply outside of everyday work life. It can show a person how much time they spend doing potentially unnecessary activities during the precious hours of their day. A Harvard Business Review showed that the U.S. wastes 7.4 billion dollars daily (a study found this information from people tracking time). Although this study was done concerning work hours, it can be understood in terms of someone&amp;rsquo;s personal life. For example, how productive is scrolling on Instagram?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
